WESLEY CHUN: Hi
WESLEY CHUN: Hi.
我是Wesley Chun  来自Google
This is Wesley Chun from Google.
你可能知道我是Python社区的成员
You may know me as a longtime member of the Python community,
但是在这个视频中  我将要使用一些Python工具
but in this episode, I'll try to actually use
向你展示如何用不到10行代码
some of those skills to show you how you can change
创建一个面向全球的应用
the world by building a globally accessible app starting
来改变世界
with just 10 lines of code.
对的  我为你下一次创业出了个主意
Yes, I'm giving you an idea for your next startup.
假设你想要做成一个非常成功的事业
Assuming you want a wildly successful business,
推向市场的时间非常重要  你需要加快脚步
time to market is of the essence, so you need to move quickly and use
并且使用工具尽快地发布你的产品
tools that get your service out there sooner.
一种方式是从一个MVP（最小可行性产品）开始
One idea is to come up with an MVP, or Minimally Viable
很快就能看见我们是否能够搭建一个web或者移动应用
Product-- quickly to see whether we can build
当然之后这些都可以有
a service without a web or mobile app, both of which can come later.
或者  你可以只是简单的做一个用户可以使用的
Instead, we can simply create a bare bones service
原型产品
that users can reach.
那我们该怎么做呢
How are we going to do that?
有什么是每个人上网时都会用到的
Well, what's one thing that everyone online has access to?
对了  电子邮件
That's right-- email.
我们会从某个人或某台电脑收到邮件
We've all got an email from a person or a computer,
你也会给别人发邮件
and you've probably sent email to a person.
但是你发过邮件给一个电脑吗
But have you ever sent email to a computer?
你待会就知道怎么实现了
Well, you're going to learn it now,
因为这可以帮助你
because that's what's allowing you
跳过第一版的原生实现
to skip native implementation for V1, because email
因为邮件服务在所有的设备上都是兼容的  不管是移动端  还是桌面端
is compatible across all devices, mobile or desktop.
这也意味着我们只专注于
This also means that we're looking
搭建一个能接收邮件的应用
at building an app that receives email.
那为什么做一个接收邮件的应用是个好主意呢
Now why is an app that receives email a big deal?
许多服务都发送email  但是这没什么意思
Well, many services send email, but that's less interesting,
因为这只是一个简单的函数调用
because it's just a single function call.
但是  接受并且处理这些信息的话
Now being able to receive and process those messages, that's
这就有趣得多  而且非常带劲
more intriguing, and as you can tell with the big bang here,
就像宇宙大爆炸一样
I think much more powerful.
你的用户向你的应用发送邮件
Your users email your service, and your app
你的应用响应这些请求
responds to those requests.
想像一下
Think about it.
你可以发送邮件给某个人
You typically email a person, but can you just as easily
但是你能向某个应用发送邮件吗
email an application?
当然
Of course.
还有  用户并不需要下载一个应用
On top of that, users don't really
因为他们的设备上
need to download another app since email is already
已经有了邮件服务
likely available on their devices.
通过允许用户向你的应用发送指令
By allowing users to send commands to your service,
你就开启了无限的可能性
you've opened up the door to many possibilities,
比如同步用户配置
such as updating user settings, transferring money
向亲戚转账  订购药品
to a relative, reordering all that prescription medicine,
淘点东西  或者开关家里或公司里的
making a small purchase, or turning on or off the TV,
电视  炉子或者闹钟
heater, or alarm at home or a business,
所有这些都通过发往你应用的
all from an email message that's coded correctly and sent
正确填写的邮件信息实现
to your service.
想像一下  先给你妈妈发邮件  然后向你的房子发邮件
Imagine emailing your mom and then emailing your house,
让它把灯关了  因为你早上赶着去机场
say to shut off the lights, because you left so early
for the airport this morning.
是不是很厉害
Doesn't that sound crazy?
自动处理也是可以升级的
Well, automated processing is also more scalable,
实现在很短的时间内同时处理成百上千的邮件
enabling the ability to process hundreds or thousands of email
然后执行这些请求
messages and performing service requests
in a very short period of time.
现在  这已经非常像一个 C/S 模型了
Now, it's very much of a client server model
如果你熟悉的话
if you're familiar with that.
话说回来  我们怎么才能通过10行以内的代码实现这些呢
So anyway, how can we possibly do this in 10 lines of code?
有了GAE的帮助
By leveraging Google App Engine, so you
你不需要了解硬件
don't have to worry about things like the hardware,
操作系统  网络编程
the operating system, network programming,
数据库  最重要的是  你甚至不需要了解email服务器
databases, and most importantly, email servers.
同样的  Python能够让你用很少的代码实现很多的功能
Similarly, Python lets you get a lot done with very few lines of code.
Python的语法非常简单  即使你不知道Python
The syntax is pretty easy, so even if you don't know Python,
你也可以跟着指南做  然后
you can still follow along in this tutorial and mentally map
用你喜欢的语言去实现
to your favorite programming language.
还有  虽然这个视频是面向初学者的
However, while this video is beginner-friendly,
但是我们不准备向你介绍如何在GAE上开发
we're not going to introduce you to developing on App Engine,
所以如果你没接触过的话  去看网站上的新手指南
so if you are new, just do the Getting Started tutorial
然后你就清楚了
that's online, and you'll be set.
准备好了之后  创建一个Hello Worldd的app
When you're ready, create a new Hello World app either
不管是用你下载GAE时的启动器
using the Launcher UI that comes with App Engine when
还是从指南中复制的代码
you download it or copy the code from the tutorial,
我们将从这儿开始
because we're going to start from there.
我们只需要修改配置文件 app.yaml
We only need to edit the app.yaml config
和主要的控制文件main.py
file and the main main.py Python controller file.
不管你信不信  搭建这个app只需要几步而已
Believe it or not, building this app only requires a few steps.
首先  创建模版应用
One, create the skeleton app.
完成
Done.
第二步  启用接收email
Step two, enable receiving email.
只需要改下配置
It's just a config change.
第三  导入email处理库
Three, bring in the library code that supports email handling.
第四  添加调用这个库的代码
Four, add the code that uses that library, and five,
最后  链接所有emai消息到那个
route all inbound email messages to the handle
第四步中写的处理器上
that you wrote in step four.
步骤二只是一个配置的修改  对吗
Step two is just a config change, right?
所以  添加这两行红色的代码
So add these two red lines of code
到你的配置文件app.yaml中
that you see here to your app.yaml config file.
这是一个新的功能  入站服务
It's a new section called Inbound Services,
在处理器功能之上运行
and it goes right above the Handler section.
GAE提供许多入站服务
App Engine supports several inbound services,
这里我们只关心email相关的
but the one we care about is email.
这就是我们需要做的
So that's what we do.
这样之后
And that's it.
你的应用现在能够接收邮件
Your app can now receive email.
其他的代码改动
All the other code changes will take place
只涉及控制器  也就是main.py  现在我们看一下
in the controller, which is main.py, so let's go there.
现在我们导入GAE中处理邮件的组件
Now let's bring in the App Engine component
that handles receiving email.
对了  我们替换掉了文件顶部
Oh, by the way, we took out the comments
自动生成的注释
that were auto-generated at the top,
这样更便于看代码
so that it's easier to see the code.
现在加上这两行红色的代码
So now add these two red lines of code.
第一行是导入logging
Line 1 is import logging.
我们在原型中要做的
What we're doing in the prototype
就是记录下应用接收到的邮件信息的发送方
is to log the senders of the email messages that our app receives.
当然你可以实现更多的功能  但是我们才刚开始
Obviously, you can do more, but we're just getting started.
第三行导入了GAE处理邮件接收的代码
Line 3 imports the App Engine code that handles the receipt of email,
这你应该能猜得出
as you can probably guess.
那为什么按这样的顺序导入文件呢
Well, why are the import lines in this order?
这是Python的推荐做法
Well, it's a Python best practice.
像logging这样系统级的导入优先
System imports like logging come first, followed by third party
其次是第三方库  比如这里的webapp2
library codes, such as webapp2.
接下来是本地SDK工具  比如GAE的API
Next are any local SDK Tools, such as the App Engine APIs,
最后  如果你要使用一些本地模块的话  这些最后导入
and finally, if we had any local modules, those would go last.
现在  我们来处理收到的邮件
Now let's handle incoming email.
这通过添加这个三行的控制类实现
This is done by adding this three-line handler class.
这个receive方法提取发送方地址并打印它
The receive method pulls out the sender's address and logs it.
你也可以获取其他的邮件属性
Now there are other email message
因为为了改变世界
attributes that you can access, because to change the world,
你要使用其他所有的东西
you're going to have to use everything
比如邮件对象和内容
else like the email subject and body
还有接收方和发送方的邮箱地址
and the sender and receiver email addresses.
最后一步  重定向所有的入站邮件请求
All right, the final step-- redirect all the inbound email
到那个我们刚刚添加的控制器上
requests to the handler that we just added.
当别人访问你的应用时
When someone points their browser at your app,
看见了Hello World  你觉得这是怎么实现的呢
and sees Hello World, how do you think that actually happens?
第14行  它把发往首页的请求跳转到
Line 14, it forwards the request for slash,
那个5~7行的MainHandler类
which is your homepage, to the main handler on lines 5 through 7.
仔细看一下13~16行那个
Think of the app variable on lines 13 through 16
作为转发表的应用变量
as the dispatch table of where we forward requests.
每个路径都是（path-handle）这样二元组的形式
Each route comes in the form of a path and handler 2-tuple
所以我们需要为进站邮件添加点东西
so we need to add something similar for inbound email.
当GAE处理入站邮件
When App Engine handles inbound email,
消息就会被发送到你的应用上的某个指定路径
messages will be posted to your app at that special path,
也就是/_ah/mail/emailaddress这样的形式
which is /_ah/mail/emailaddress.
既然我们要用同一个处理器处理这些邮件
Since we're going to handle all emails with the same handler,
我们需要使用一个正则表达式
we'll use a regular expression-- or regex--
匹配所有这样的地址  因此我们使用了(.+)
matching all such addresses, hence why we have dot plus.
用于重定向到邮件处理器
That redirects to email handler.
对了  别忘了第14行末尾的逗号
Oh, by the way, don't forget that trailing comma
这也就是这行被标红的原因
at the end of line 14, which is why it's kind of red too.
否则的话  就会报错
Otherwise, you'll get a runtime error.
我刚刚帮你解决了一个面试问题
Hey, I just helped you pass an interview question,
高兴去吧
so feel good about it.
这就是全部要做的了
And that's it.
不算导入语句和空行的话
Ignoring the imports and blank lines,
我们只用差不多10行代码完成了所有工作
we're left with about 10 lines of code that do all the work.
如果你非常严格
Now if you're really pedantic and recognize
而且认为那个转发表只是一个简单的Python语句的话
that the routing table is actually just one single Python
那么就只有7行了
statement, well, you can cut that down to seven,
如果你只计算我们添加的代码的话
and if you're only counting the number of lines that we added,
那么就只有6行了
well, it's down to six.
天哪
Amazing!
这就是一个完整的可以实现基本功能的应用了
Believe it or not, this is a fully working app that does the basics.
我们没有创建一个web应用  除非你算上那个Hello World字符
We don't have a web app, unless you count the Hello World bit,
我们也没有创建一个Android或者iOS移动客户端  对吗
and neither did we create an Android or iOS mobile client, right?
但是你也可以去做
But you could.
通过使用Google Cloud Endpoints
And easily, by using Google Cloud Endpoints.
你可以点开上面的视频观看
You can click on the video there and check it out.
好了
All right.
现在我们启动它
Now let's run it.
GAE的SDK自带了一个部署服务器  或开发服务器
The App Engine SDK comes with a development server, or dev
你可以在把你的应用发布到Google上之前
server, which lets you run your app
在本地运行调试它
locally to test with before you deploy live to Google.
不管你是通过启动器  还是通过命令行
When you do this by either clicking run on the launcher UI
在本地运行你的应用之前
or using the command line tool, make sure, by the way,
请确保你已经记下了应用的端口号和管理员控制台的端口号
that you note the port numbers for both the main app as well
因为我们都要用到
as the admin console, because we're going to use both.
用你的浏览器访问localhost:8080
Point your browser at the main app at local host 8080.
你就会看到控制器输出了Hello World
You should see the main handler in action rendering Hello World.
因为我们在开发模式  所以你只能模拟发送邮件
Since we're only in dev, you can only simulate sending email.
通过访问控制台的开发服务器
And to do that, you need to get to the dev server admin console.
所以现在用别的端口（8000）访问你的浏览器
So now point your browser at the other port, which is local host 8000.
到了这步
Once you're there, what we really want
我们实际需要的就是左边栏里的入站邮件链接
is the inbound mail link in the left nav, so click that.
点开它  你就会看到这个用来发送模拟邮件的表单
You'll see this form to send a fake email with.
在这之前  我来说一下我们首先要发送的是什么
Before we do that, let's talk about what we're sending first.
你要清楚你需要验证每一条邮件
Recognize you're going to have to validate every message,
因为你需要确保每个请求都是真的
because you're going to need to make sure that every request is
不是垃圾邮件  也不是虚假邮件
real, not spam, not fake, and most importantly,
最重要的 不是被劫持的邮件
not sent by someone on behalf of someone else.
这样的话  未认证用户发来的没有遵守你的服务条款的
Invalid messages coming from unrecognized users that
非法邮件
don't follow your security protocol
比如一个短语密码或者两个元素验证
like a secret passphrase or two factor auth
或者只是没有正确构造的
or just aren't structured correctly
就会被丢弃或者被记录下来
can simply be dropped or logged as desired.
在这里的邮件正文中  你可以看见
As you can see in the message body here,
我们有许多的工具可以用来达成这个目的
we've got a lot of stuff that can be potentially used
如果我们在构建多个原型
for this purpose if we were creating more than just a prototype.
好的
All right.
业务逻辑就是这样
Enough business logic.
下面我们讲一下发送邮件
Let's talk about sending email.
GAE的应用会接收所有发送到
So App Engine apps receive email sent to any address
xxx@APP_ID.appspotmail.com这样地址的邮件
of the format xxx@APP_ID.appspotmail.com,
这里的xxx是收件人  你的应用ID就是主机名
where xxx is a recipient, and your app ID is the host.
确保在域名中使用appspotmail而不是appspot.com
Be sure to use appspotmail in the domain name rather than appspot.com.
在这个例子中  我们假装已经为我们的新闻小组
In this demo, let's pretend I created this awesome service
创建了完善的服务  让他们能够
for our press team, allowing them to issue new press
通过简单的命令发布新闻
releases with a single command.
我们使用发布命令
We're using the Publish command for the recipient.
接收邮件的是我们虚假的应用ID
Receiving email is our fake app ID.
对了  这是我找到的的别人的应用
By the way, that's really someone else's app,
所以在生产模式下
so don't send anything there if you're
不要发送东西到那个地址
going to run in production.
在开发模式中  这是没关系的
It doesn't really matter in the dev server
因为实际上并没有邮件被发送
as no emails are actually sent.
一旦你点击了发送  并且受到了请求成功的消息
Once you click Send and see Request Succeeded message,
检查一下你的打印日志  确认一下你的处理器被调用了
check your logs and verify that your handler was called.
点击启动器上的记录按钮
Click the Logs button in the launcher
或者查看发送到控制台的命令行消息
or check out the command line output sent to the console.
你会看到  已收到一条消息
You should see Received a Message
来自那个你设置的虚拟地址
From whatever fake sender address you used.
在生产模式下运行之前还需要做一些事情
Running this live in production requires only a few more steps.
请确保你已经把那个唯一的ID
Make sure you've got that unique ID plugged
配置在了app.yaml文件里
into your app.yaml file.
然后去启动器  点击发布按钮
Then go to the launcher, and click
你的代码就会在验证之后被发布到Google上
Deploy to send your code to Google after authenticating.
也可以使用命令行工具
Or you can also use the command line tool.
应用上线以后
Once the app's uploaded, check that it's
你只需在浏览器中访问yourappID.appspot.com
up by going to the Hello World page in the browser
看看是否有Hello World页面  确认是否已经生效
just like we did for the dev server,
就像我们在开发服务器上做的一样
only you'll be pointing at yourappID.appspot.com.
现在  打开你最喜欢的邮件客户端
Now pull up your favorite, warm, cozy-up-by-the-fireplace email
向你的应用发送一条真正的邮件
client to send a real email message to your app.
同样的  你需要发送到xxx@yourappid.appspotmail.com这样的地址
Again, it should go to some xxx@yourappid.appspotmail.com.
然后去你在cloud.google.com/console上应用控制台
After sending, go to your Apps Admin Console
选择你的应用
at cloud.google.com/console, selecting your app,
点击左边栏上的App Engine
and clicking App Engine in the left nav bar.
点击App Engine自菜单中  点击logs
In the App Engine sub nav bar, click on logs.
你就会在屏幕中看到你想要的
In the middle of the admin screen,
你的邮件处理器的
you should see exactly what you wanted-- your email handler's
打印日志
log message.
真棒
Booyah!
我们接下来要做什么呢
What do we do next?
如果你想跳过编码
Well, if you want to skip the typing
直接看源码的话  点击这个链接
and get straight to the source, click the link
下载压缩文件
to download the zip file.
或者  你想要一步步实现的话
If for some reason, you want a slower step-by-step,
在GAE的核心Python应用编程中
a full treatment can be found in the Google App Engine
你可以找到一个手把手的教程
chapter of Core Python Applications Programming.
总而言之
Otherwise, that's it.
我们刚刚一起创建了一个GAE的Python应用
We've just built a Python App Engine app together.
这个应用能够接收邮件
It can receive email.
不到10行代码
It's less than or equal to 10 lines of code.
现在轮到你改变世界了
Now it's up to you to change the world.
说真的  你已经拥有了开启一个新的事业的素质了
Seriously, you've got the makings of a new business here.
继续做吧  在Google云平台上走上人生巅峰
Go out, and be successful on the Google Cloud Platform.
感谢收看
Thanks for tuning in.